<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tags on Orson Hart</title>
    <link>https://orsonhart.com/tags/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tags on Orson Hart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://orsonhart.com/tags/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing is Hard</title>
      <link>https://orsonhart.com/writing-is-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orsonhart.com/writing-is-hard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I would love to be a good writer, but I find it very difficult to communicate my thoughts eloquently through text. I often find what I write to be clumsy and unnatural to read, and so I find it useful to edit my written thoughts by reading them out loud and correcting whatever feels strange to say. I read books that aren&amp;rsquo;t written how someone would speak, though, so perhaps there is a voice exclusive to written form that I need to master.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want this website to be a place where I can write medium to long form thoughts on topics that I find interesting. Mainly as a way to practice writing, but also because sometimes I might think my ideas are actually worth sharing. Some of these ideas are maths adjacent, mainly relating to how I study mathematics effectively, and I think these will probably be easiest for me to write because it&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m most familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know the best way to improve my writing will just be to practice writing more, but I also feel like I don&amp;rsquo;t want to write &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt; thoughts either. I think it is probably best to just bite the bullet and &lt;strong&gt;just write&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Short URLs</title>
      <link>https://orsonhart.com/short-urls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orsonhart.com/short-urls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went back and forth on how to structure URLs for this website. On reading Derek Sivers&amp;rsquo; post &lt;a href=&#34;https://sive.rs/su&#34;&gt;Short URLs: why and how&lt;/a&gt;, I agreed with his reasons - they look nicer and are easier to type and remember - and so thought it would be good to implement his suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;domain&#34;&gt;Domain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to use &lt;code&gt;orsonh.art&lt;/code&gt; as a shorter (and more fun) domain name, and I was planning on using single word or abbreviated URLs. I instantly ran into my first problem. &lt;strong&gt;Ease of communication&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;orsonh.art&lt;/code&gt; is easier to type, but harder to communicate. As a comment on Sivers&amp;rsquo; original post notes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love the philosophy of short URLS. The only barrier I&amp;rsquo;ve found is communicating them verbally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to explain my cool new URL to a handful of people, and it always took longer for them to understand than the simpler &lt;code&gt;orsonhart.com&lt;/code&gt;. Another upside to using &lt;code&gt;orsonhart.com&lt;/code&gt; is that &lt;code&gt;.com&lt;/code&gt; is a universally recognised, and more sensible, top-level domain. A friend of mine said &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;orsonh.art sounds like your an artist named orsonh&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did, however, drop the &lt;code&gt;www.&lt;/code&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s much nicer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-links&#34;&gt;Post Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After writing a single post, one of the disadvantages of short URLs &lt;a href=&#34;https://qntm.org/urls&#34;&gt;mentioned by qntm&lt;/a&gt; became apparent, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;You do actually have to think of something.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. It is hard &lt;em&gt;(impossible?)&lt;/em&gt; to write a meaningful link using very few characters. I like the fact that a slightly longer, although still concise, URL gives you information about the link you are clicking on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very few people will remember or type a URL. Most will follow a link posted elsewhere, and so I decided to prioritise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clarity over conciseness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information over aesthetic.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cleanness over clutter.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Archiving Hamish and Andy</title>
      <link>https://orsonhart.com/podcast-archiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://orsonhart.com/podcast-archiving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a digital minimalist, I often want to spend time disconnected. To limit the amount of time I spend using a smartphone, I like to listen to music, audiobooks, and podcasts on my 2009 iPod Classic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One challenge is that some media is resistant to being accessed offline. This includes my absolute favourite - the Hamish and Andy podcast - which has its entire back catalogue &lt;a href=&#34;https://handa.libsyn.com/&#34;&gt;available on Libsyn&lt;/a&gt; available with a premium subscription. This post will explain how to download these premium podcasts for archiving or offline listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: These instructions are designed to work on Windows.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools-required&#34;&gt;Tools Required&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A premium Hamish and Andy subscription&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yt-dlp/yt-dlp&#34;&gt;yt-dlp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;steps&#34;&gt;Steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a folder for your downloads and put &lt;code&gt;yt-dlp.exe&lt;/code&gt; here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login to Libsyn and navigate to the page at &lt;a href=&#34;https://handa.libsyn.com/&#34;&gt;handa.libsyn.com&lt;/a&gt; listing the podcasts you want to download. Scroll to the bottom to load them all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the developer console and use &lt;code&gt;console.log([...document.querySelectorAll(&amp;quot;h2 &amp;gt; a.read_more&amp;quot;)].map(x =&amp;gt; x.href).join(&amp;quot;\n&amp;quot;))&lt;/code&gt; to get a list of urls. Save these in your folder as &lt;code&gt;urls.txt&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Terminal and run the command
&lt;code&gt;yt-dlp  --cookies-from-browser BROWSER --batch-file urls.txt -o &amp;quot;/YYYY/MM/%(upload_date&amp;gt;%Y-%m-%d)s %(title)s.%(ext)s&amp;quot; --parse-metadata &amp;quot;title:- %(title)s&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;. Make sure to replace &lt;code&gt;BROWSER&lt;/code&gt; with the name of your browser e.g. &lt;code&gt;chrome&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/YYYY/MM&lt;/code&gt; with the appropriate year and month, e.g. &lt;code&gt;/2013/02&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt;  The &lt;code&gt;--parse-metadata&lt;/code&gt; flag stops &amp;ldquo;Hamish &amp;amp; Andy&amp;rdquo; from duplicating in the filename if the podcast titles incude &amp;ldquo;Hamish &amp;amp; Andy -&amp;rdquo;, and can be removed if appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let &lt;code&gt;yt-dlp&lt;/code&gt; run and all the podcast files should be downloaded to the specified &lt;code&gt;/YYYY/MM&lt;/code&gt; folder. A screenshot of the podcasts from February 2013 is below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://orsonhart.com/handa_list.png&#34; alt=&#34;handa_list&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
